Stefan Eilemann

Faubourg de l'Hôpital 12 · CH-2000 Neuchâtel · +41 76 33 77 247 · eilemann@gmail.com

Particulars Date of Birth 9th August 1975

Birth Place Wittenberg, Germany Nationality German, Swiss Permit C

Profile

Senior software engineer and architect, with a specialization in high performance 3D graphics, C++, parallelization of applications and distributed systems. Consultant and contractor delivering solutions and expertise to enhance existing applications and to create new software.

EXPERTISE

- High performance OpenGL applications, parallel programming, distributed systems, Virtual Reality.
- Software design, development and maintenance using C++, Java, Perl in various programming environments.
- Software development methodology during the whole lifecycle, ranging from requirements analysis, specification, design, implementation to documentation, education, debugging, profiling and support.
- In-depth knowledge of standard graphics technologies, including OpenGL, Equalizer, Chromium, OpenSceneGraph, graphics clusters and hardware.
- Broad knowledge of operating systems: Mac OS X, Linux (x86/IA64), Windows, Irix) and distributed computing.
- Native german speaker, fluent english, good french knowledge.

EDUCATION

Berufakademie Heidenheim

Dipl.-Ing. (eq BS) in Computer Science, September 1998

Lucas-Cranach-Gymnasium Wittenberg

Abitur (university entrance qualification), June 1994

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer and Consultant Neuchâtel, Switzerland Eyescale Software GmbH January 2007 – current

Working on the parallelization of customer applications in order to scale the display size and performance for 3D rendering. Design and development of scalable, parallel graphics applications as well as general 3D graphics software and hardware consulting.

Researcher, Parallel Rendering Zürich, Switzerland University of Zürich March 2005 – current

Initiated and developed Equalizer, a framework for the creation of distributed, scalable graphics software. Current research includes new algorithms for the parallelization, management and loadbalancing of applications on multiuser graphics clusters.

Senior Software Engineer, 3D Graphics Neuchâtel, Switzerland Tungsten Graphics January 2007 – June 2007

Software consultant for visualization clusters. Ported Equalizer to Windows XP, ported Chromium to Mac OS X and demonstrated Google Earth, Amira and other unmodified applications on a big display wall at WWDC07.

Senior Software Engineer Neuchâtel, Switzerland

Developed Java software in Esmertec's R&D group which enables user interface customization on mobile devices and desktops. Designed and implemented a fully functional 3D phone simulator for customer presentations.

Senior Software Engineer Neuchâtel, Switzerland Silicon Graphics, Inc. August 2000 – December 2003

Worked in SGI's advanced graphics division as technical lead for OpenGL Multipipe SDK (MPK). MPK is a C/C++framework to develop high performance, scalable visualization software. Worked on DataSync, a distributed shared memory API for clusters.

Software Engineer Munich, Germany

Freelancer April 2000 – July 2000

Wrote a network configuration management solution for the internet backbone of Cable & Wireless, using Linux, Apache, MySQL and Perl.

Software Engineer
Wessling, Germany

Intec GmbH October 1998 – March 2000

Worked as software engineer in the software development team for SIMPACK, a multibody simulation program. Responsible for maintaining the existing 2D and 3D graphics subsystem based on PHIGS, as well rewriting it to use Open Inventor.

References are available on request.